Lucas Nakeli

Front-End Developer

<u>Iuminouslucas@duck.com</u>

Github: DManLucas

▶ Portfolio: Lucas.genius



(+27) 61 482 4560

In LinkedIn: Lucas Nakeli

31 Cromwell Road, Navalsig 16 Pastell Cottage,Bloemfontein

In my current role as a Frontend Web Developer, I have developed web-based applications from design to coding and full implementation. By relying on solid programming knowledge as well as excellent oral and verbal communication I have consistently produced terrific code within customer-set deliverable time frames. My commitment is staying up-to-date with all technological advancements and growing as a developer.

Specializing in: Javcascript, NodeJS, React, HTML5, CSS3, TailwindCSS and SCSS.

Education	
Jan 2019 - Dec 2019	
Jan 2015 – Dec 2017	
Jan 2019 - Dec 2019	

Professional Experience

Front-end developer, Leverage BPO

May 2021 - Dec 2022

- Given tasks on different types of websites already designed by the company and update them or fix issues that come up while they're on the web.
- Design templates for usage for companies and implement the templates.
- Change the look of old websites and use the latest coding principles.
- Design mobile-based features and ensure web design is optimized for smartphones.
- Optimizing web pages for maximum speed and scalability.
- Help Backend developers with coding and troubleshooting.
- Maintaining brand consistency throughout the design.
- Going through a prepared task list based on a deadline.
- Weekly meetings for work done and changes that were done.
- Turn UI/UX designs into prototypes, creating excellent interactions. Write reusable code and libraries to a standard that makes it quick and easy to maintain the code in the future.

Lecturer, <u>ATTI Bloemfontein</u>

Sep 2019 - Dec 2019

- Accessed students work through the CMS system for marking and also giving out work
- Taught End User and CompTIA
- Practical work

Front-end developer, <u>Ooweboo</u>

Sep 2017 - Jan 2018

- Worked directly with business owners to create and deploy performant websites and mobile applications.
- Built stable and maintainable codebases using custom WordPress templates or from scratch with HTML and CSS

- •Completed four major projects, working closely with the agile development team to develop, test, and maintain websites.
- Adhered to high-quality development standards while delivering solutions on time.
- Write reusable code and libraries to a standard that makes it quick and easy to maintain the code in the future.
- Morning meetings for work to be done during the day.

Freelance Developer, Various

Feb 2018 -

Worked directly with business owners to create and deploy performant websites

- Built stable and maintainable websites using JavaScript, HTML5, WordPress and CSS3.
- Developed a mobile application with **React Native** for viewing, generating and sending transactional documents.
- Change the look of old websites and use the latest coding principles.

Technical Skills

- Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, CSSpreprocessors (SASS/SCSS), PHP & C# (working-knowledge), WordPress
- Frameworks & Libraries: NextJS, React, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap.
- Tools: Git, Github, NPM, CPanel, Figma.
- Services: Netlify, Vercel, Firebase.

Noteworthy Projects

WhatsApp clone, WhatsAppLucas

Designed and developed a WhatsApp clone

- Implemented **WhatsApp clone** using NextJs that has1-1 Messaging, Live Status, used Styled-Components, React.JS and hosted through Netlify from **Github**.
- Used **Firebase** for storing data, creating a chat and google authentication.

MixMatchLucas, Mix Match Game

Designed a Halloween themed card matching game

 Used JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS to code the game with Halloween music themed and also image assets.

Reddlucas, Reddlucas

Designed a Reddit clone based website

Built a Reddit clone from scratch using React, Firebase, Next.js, Chakra UI, and TypeScript. The application features authentication, Firestore database, cloud functions, security rules, Transactions, deployment